The Walking Dead: The Return is a documentary film directed by Jes Thorud.
Stars of "The Walking Dead," Andrew Lincoln and Danai Gurira, walk down memory lane and visit iconic
locations where pivotal moments between their characters, Rick and Michonne, were filmed.
Self / Rick Grimes, played by Andrew Lincoln.
Self / Michonne Hawthorne, played by Danai Gurira.
Daryl Dixon (archive footage), played by Norman Reedus.
Negan Smith (archive footage), played by Jeffrey Dean Morgan.
Carl Grimes (archive footage), played by Chandler Riggs.
Glenn Rhee (archive footage), played by Steven Yeun.
The Walking Dead is an American zombie apocalypse media franchise centered on a
number of television series based on the comic book of the same name.
Set in one fictional shared universe, the franchise has developed into seven live-action television series, eight
web series that tie into the first two television series, novels, video games, and other media.
The television series all air on AMC and AMC+.
The Walking Dead comic book was initially adapted into The
Walking Dead television series (2010–2022).
It was followed by the spin-off series Fear the Walking Dead (2015–2023), The Walking Dead: World
Beyond (2020–2021), and the anthology series Tales of the Walking Dead (2022).
Following the conclusion of the original television series, three further spin-off series have been released featuring returning main characters: The Walking Dead: Dead City (2023–present), which focuses
on Negan and Maggie; The Walking Dead: Daryl Dixon (2023–present), which focuses on Daryl and Carol; and The Walking Dead: The Ones Who Live (2024), which focuses on Rick and Michonne.
Another series entitled More Tales from the Walking
Dead Universe is in development.
The film explores themes of behind the scenes,
filmmaking, making of, documentary filmmaking.